おぉあっ！
でえぇやあっ！
ふん！
たあ！
Retreat!
て 撤退だあ！
やったああー！ わああー！
ふうー！ わあああー…！
ふん
We did it, huh, Kid!?
やったなあ あんちゃん
わあー ヒューヒュー！ わあああー！
kodomo no goro no yume wa
The dream I had when I was a child,
子供の頃の夢は 色褪せない落書きで
iroase nai rakugaki de
were drawn to my heart's desire
omou mama kaki suberasete
with scribbles that wouldn't fade away
思うまま書き滑らせて
描く未来へとつながる
egaku mirai he to tsunagaru
and are connected to the future i draw.
Utawarerumono
sumiwataru sora
The clear skies
澄み渡る空 果てしないほど青く
hateshinai hodo aoku
were endlessly blue.
mujaki na kokoro ni
And my innocent heart,
無邪気な心に 充たされ魅かれてく
mitasare hikareteku
being satisfied, was attracted to them.
yagate jiyuu ni tobimawareru
I finally obtained wings
やがて自由に飛びまわれる
翼（はね）を手に入れて
hane wo teni irete
with which I could fly freely.
muku na hitomi wa motometeku
I want to go to the end of the skies
無垢な瞳は求めてく
空の向こうへ 行きたいな
sora no mukou he ikitai na
which my pure eyes desire.
kore tonai negai kara
If one wish could be granted
止め処ない願いから 一つだけ叶うのなら
hitotsu dake kanau no nara
out of countless others...
dare ni mo yuzuri taku wa nai
I feel that it should be to grab onto a dream
誰にも譲りたくはない
夢を掴みたいと思うよ
yume wo tsukamitai to omou yo
and never be tempted to let go.
kodomo no goro no yume wa
The dreams I had when I was a child,
子供の頃の夢は 色褪せない落書きで
iroase nai rakugaki de
were drawn eternally,
itsuwademo kaki tsuzukerareta
with scribbles that wouldn't fade away
いつまでも描き続けられた
願う未来へとつながる
negau mirai he to tsunagaru
and are connected to the future I wish for.
Invasion of the Imperial City
With today's battle, we have secured
a majority of the east,
今日の戦で ここを中心に
東の部分は ほぼ制圧
and this region has been secured
by our allies as well.
この地域も 我々の傘下に入った
豪族達が制圧した
Sheesh, what a fickle lot!
ったーく 調子のいい奴らだ
They change their allegiances
as soon as things go south,
散々インカラに尻尾を振っときながら
even though they've wagged their tails
for Inkalla all this time.
ちょっと旗色が悪くなりゃ すぐこれだ
Come on, this means we have more
allies now. It's a good thing!
まあ 仲間が増えたんだ　いいってことよ
-だーっはっはっはっ…！
-左右は固めた
We've secured their flanks.
Brother!
兄者
Do not be hasty. Failure will not be tolerated.
早まるな
失敗は許されない
We will crush the forces that currently
occupy the central region.
この中央に陣取る敵勢力を 撃破する
Aren't you going to sleep?
お休みにならないんですか？
No...
アルルゥはどうしてる？
How is Aruruu?
She's playing with Mukkuru, as usual.
相変わらずムックルと遊んでいます
I see.
そうか
Hakuoro-san, I have a favor to ask.
ハクオロさん
お願いがあるんです
Is it all right for you to be up now?
起きていて大丈夫なのかい？
Yes, I was listening to the
sounds of the night.
はい
夜の音を聴いていました
Sounds of the night?
夜の音？
うう！ 兄者は！
Brother!
These are all the survivors, Samurai General.
侍大将
生き残りは これで全員です
Good, kill them!
よーし やれ
What are you waiting for?
Hurry up and kill them!
何をしてる！ さっさとやらねえか！
But, Samurai General, these people are...
しかし侍大将　この者達は…
うるせえ！
Shut up!
Don't you go soft! This is war!
甘っちょろいこと抜かしてんじゃねえ
We kill them when we can!
これは戦だ！
やれる時にはやるんだよ！
うっ う ひい！
んっ くうっ！
What are you doing?
Hurry up and kill him!
な 何してるー！
早くやれぇー！
Wh.. What!?
な 何！
わあああー！ いぃやああー！
くっ あいつ…
That man...
Nuwangi!
ヌワンギ
That bastard!
あの野郎！
Don't leave a single one alive!
Kill them all!
１人残らず ぶっ殺せ！
3nd Unit, distract the enemy forces,
along with Dori and Gura!
第３陣とドリィ グラァは
敵の目を引き付けよ！
The main unit will charge in from behind.
本陣は裏から回り込む！
Dori! Gura!
ドリィ！ グラァ！
Leave it to us!
お任せください！
Charge on! Don't lose to the likes of them!
もっと攻めろ！
そんな奴らに負けんじゃねえー！
What?
何！
どりゃあー！
てえっ！
ううっ　ふん！
General! We're all doomed at this rate!
侍大将！
このままでは全滅です！
They've completely taken the front!
完全に風上を押さえられました！
Then close your eyes and fight forward,
you spineless jerk!
だったら目をつぶって戦えー！
腰抜け野郎！
Don't run! Don't run away!
逃げるな！ 逃げるんじゃねえ！
You call yourselves Samurai General
Nuwangi's 1st Unit?
それでもヌワンギ侍大将
１番部隊かあー！
ああっ　くっ… おわああー！
ぬうう！ うっ うう　うう…
The battle has been decided.
勝負は決した
Further resistance is futile.
これ以上の抵抗は無駄だ
So it is you after all...
結局は てめえか
へへっ　へえ
In the end, I've been abandoned.
最後は見捨てられちまったかい
Pretty pathetic, isn't it?
こうなると哀れなもんだなあ
Talk about sad shape, I'll tell you...
ざまぁねえなあ
全くよお
Go on, kill me.
Hurry up and kill me!
さっ やれよ！
さっさと やれっつってんだよ！
It seems you're prepared for it.
覚悟は できてるみたいだね
なっ エルルゥ！
Eruruu!?
ふっ　笑いたきゃ笑えよ
Laugh if you want.
You must feel good, seeing me
in this miserable state.
惨めな姿を見て さぞ気分がいいだろうな
So, what shall we do, brother?
で どうする兄者
Do you want me to kill him?
Or would you rather throw him in a cell?
さっさとやるか
それとも牢にでも ぶち込んどくか
Eruruu, what would you like to do?
エルルゥ
どうする
Please, let Nuwangi go.
ヌワンギを放してあげてください
-まさか…
-放しちまうのかよお
What's going on?
どういうことだ
But that's what Eruruu's decided...
でもエルルゥが決めたことだ
You're sure about this?
いいんだね
Yes.
はい
Looks like it's decided.
決まったみてえだなあ
Goodbye.
さようなら
ふん
All units, attack!
全軍 進撃ー！
-うあああー！
-続けええー！
Forward!
ふん！ ううっ　ふあ！
おりゃあー！ ふっ ふっ ふっ！
We have completely surrounded
the Imperial City.
これで皇都は完全に包囲した
Tomorrow, we will attack it all at once.
あすは一気に攻め上がる
So the time has finally come.
とうとう来たんだなあ　この時がよお
This will be the end of it.
これで終わる
Brother!
兄者
Begging your pardon, Sire!
The enemy is headed this way!
申し上げます！
敵本陣が こちらに向かってきています！
Have Nuwangi take care of it.
ヌワンギにやらせるにゃも
Unfortunately, the Samurai General is
still missing since the last defeat.
残念ながら 侍大将は先の合戦にて敗退
いまだに行方不明です
That useless punk...
役立たずにゃもね
Then you all handle it somehow.
だったら おみゃあらで何とかするにゃも
Yes, Sire!
ほら 急げ！
Brother!
兄者
第３陣から第５陣は左翼
Have the 3rd through 5th units
take the left flank,
while the 6th through 9th units
take the right flank.
第６陣から第９陣は右翼へ回る
The 1st Unit will attack from the center.
第１陣は中央突破
Time to do it!
出番だに
Leave it to us!
まーかせとけえ！
だああー！
-うう！
-うぅあっ！
うぅあああー！
ほあっ！
うらああー！
ええ！ ほわああー！ おわあー！
えっ えっ　あわああーっ！
うっ うっ　うううー！
ええーやっ！
でええぇー！
わああー！ うわあ！
Now!
今だあ！
ううぅあああー！
Brother!
兄者！
Attack!
出るぞ！
ふあっ！ ふっ はっ！
いよおおー！
ぬううう…！ ふん！
ふんっ ふんっ ふんっ！
いぃや！ うう…
ふん！
No sense hanging around.
長居は無用か
えやっ！
へあっ！
Find Inkalla! We must find Inkalla!
インカラだ！
インカラを捜すんだ！
Understood!
承知
I've come for you, General.
迎えに来やしたぜ！ 大将
What? Are you serious?
えっ 本気ですかい？
But General, you must have realized by now.
でも大将 気づいているはずですぜ
There's nothing left to defend here.
この國にはもう 守るべき価値は無いって
I suppose so.
そうですね
もはや この國の崩壊は必然でしょう
This country's ruin is already certain.
Then why do this!?
だったら どうして
Any country would be honored to take you in!
大将なら どの國だって
高く受け入れてくれやす
In fact, if you wanted to...
いや 大将さえ その気なら…
That's enough.
そこまでです
I appreciate your thoughts.
あなたの心遣いは感謝します
However, I am still this country's
Samurai General.
ですが
それでも私は この國の侍大将なのですよ
I am obligated to align my destiny
with that of this country.
私には この國と運命を
共にする義務があるのです
General, you couldn't mean...
大将…
まさか
Let us go.
行きましょう
これが最後の戦となります
This will be our final battle.
Then I guess I should live it up!
ほんじゃあ いっちょ
派手にやりますか！
Benawi!?
ベナウィ
うぅーわっ！
Quit playing around here.
こんなとこで遊んでないで
さっさと帰って ねんねでもしてな！
Just go home and take a nap!
So he's here too, huh?
あいつもいたのか
You will not step aside, will you?
引いては くれないのだな
Then I'll take you down so we can move on!
ならば
倒して進むまでだあー！ ふっ！
It seems you've been promoted.
精進したようですね
Mind your own damn business!
余計なお世話だ！
Samurai General!
侍大将ー！
兄者！
Brother! I'll take care of these guys!
こいつらは俺が引き受けた！
ふん！
へえっ！
ん えやっ！ ああ！
ふん！
うぅーわああ！ かっ…
Just one more push, everyone!
皆ー あと一息だあー！
おおー！ ふっ ふっ
うやああー！ はあっ！
うぅーわ　うう！
General!
大将
Benawi!
ベナウィ！
Wait a minute.
おっと待った
Sorry, but I can't let you through.
悪いが ここを通すわけには
いかねえんでなあ
Brother!
兄者！
ぷふうー ぷふううー
Benawi, did you chase them away?
ベナウィ
奴らは追い払ったにゃもか？
Regrettably, we have been defeated.
遺憾ながら 私達の敗北です
What?
にゃーも？
Don't be silly.
バーカなことを言うでないにゃも
Do something. Send the men to slay them.
刺し違えてでも何とかするにゃも
１人につき１人刺し違えれば
最後には勝利にゃも
If each man slays one of the enemy,
then we will be victorious in the end.
Our forces are nearly annihilated.
我が軍は ほぼ全滅
It is unlikely we'll be able to alter
the course of battle now.
もはや戦況を覆すことは不可能でしょう
What?
え にゃーも？
のおっ！
うっ ははあ！
んっ だったら すぐ逃げるにゃも
Then we must escape immediately!
Where will you run to?
どこへお逃げになるのです
We are surrounded, escape is impossible.
もう取り囲まれ
逃げることは叶いますまい
If they capture you, you'll be
crucified, then beheaded.
奴らに捕えられれば 磔の上に さらし首
An emperor's pride would never
allow such a death.
そのような死にざまは 皇（オゥルォ）としての
誇りが許されないでしょう
I thought you would prefer to
take your own life.
割腹なされるのが よろしいかと
As such, it shall be my solemn duty
to assist you in this.
僭越ながら わたくしが
介錯を務めさせて頂きます
んっ にゃも？ ううっ
What!?
-ふん
-うっ！
でぇい！
Brother! I'll take care of this guy.
兄者
こいつは俺が引き受けた
I'm counting on you!
頼んだぞ！
Wait!
待て！
What are you looking at?
どこ 見てんだよお！
N.. No!
嫌にゃも！
I don't want to die yet!
まだ死にたくないにゃも！
There's more tasty food to eat and
more beautiful women to play with!
おいしい物をもっと食べて 美しい
おなごと もっと遊ぶにゃもお　うう…
-うっ…
-皇たる者
Shouldn't an emperor depart in
a more dignified manner?
最後は潔く果てるべきではありませんか
No, no, no!
嫌にゃも 嫌にゃも 嫌にゃもおー！
It will be my final duty to send
you off on my own.
ならば この手でお送りすること
最後の務めとさせて頂きます
ひっ ひっ うぅーうう！ ああ ああ！
ひい あっ わあ わあっ！
うっ ひぎぃ！ ぎゃがああー…！
The emperor has departed.
聖上は崩御されました
Please inform everyone that
this battle has ended.
戦は終わったと 皆にお伝えください
Please take care of this country...
and all the other matters.
この國を
後のことは よろしく頼みます
You will not allow me to die?
死なせてはくれないのですか
You would try to run away like that?
勝手に逃げる気か
Is it not your duty to see things
through to the end?
お前には最後まで
見届ける責任があるはずだ
You wish to have me live on in shame?
私に生き恥をさらせと
Brother?
兄者
General?
大将
What's going on?
どうしたんだろう
え？ 何だ？
Inkalla is dead.
インカラは死んだ
The war has ended.
戦は終わった
-え？ ええ？
-インカラが死んだ？
Inkalla's dead!?
-死んだって
-おい
We won! We won!
やったああー！ やったぜええー！
Hurray!
いぃーやっふう！
We did it... We finally did it!
やったんだな
とうとうやったんだ！
So it's over, huh?
終わっちまったか
What a sorry sight.
全く 何てざまだ
How pathetic...
情けねえ
If I knew this was going to happen,
I would have gone out in a blaze.
こんなことなら ド派手に
討ち死にした方がよかったぜ
Please don't say such a thing.
そんなこと言わないでください
Because there are those you'd
leave behind after you die.
旅立った後は
残される人がいるんですから
General, we sure lost this one.
大将　本当に負けちまいましたよ
So it would seem.
そのようですね
-ウワァー アッ アッ ウゥーウ　ワゥ…
-あっ ああ　あっははは　ふふ
Those are the details.
以上が詳細となります
Yet another country has fallen?
また１つ國が滅びたか
はい
Yes, the new country's name is "Tuskuru".
新たな國の名はトゥスクルとのこと
Tuskuru!?
トゥスクル
And its emperor's name?
して 皇の名は
My apologies, we do not know yet.
申し訳ございませんが そこまでは
I see.
そうか
Then Munto, I shall place you in charge
of dispatching a delegation.
ではムントよ
使節団の派遣 そなたに任せよう
Your Holiness!
オルヤンクル
Please allow me to take that mission!
そのお役目 わたくしに
お申し付け頂けませんか？
Princess! That will not do!
ひっ 姫様
それはなりません！
I'm sure the country is still in chaos
so soon after the war.
戦乱後 間もない地
國はいまだ混沌としておりましょう
I'll be all right, Munto.
大丈夫ですよ ムント
うふ ふっ
Very well, then.
いいだろう
You express your wish as a priestess,
so you no doubt have your reasons.
カムナギである そなたが言うのだ
何か思うところがあるのだろう
Thank you very much.
ありがとうございます
は はあ オルヤンクル！
Your Holiness!?
うふ ふっ
うっふふ ふっ
Well, now that's interesting!
いいこと聞いちゃった
炎さえも凍てついた
honou sae mo itetsuita
I seek the solitude
孤独の中求む
kokuno naka moto mu
that freezes even flames.
魂から結びつき 私を恋い温めて
tamashi kara musubitsuki
Connecting with your soul,
watashi wo koi atatamete
warm me with your love.
嗚呼 祈りの言葉がふるえ
a inori no kotoba ga furue
Ah...the words of prayer tremble...
嗚呼 弱きいのちが消えても
a yowaki no chika kiete mo
Ah even if the faint-hearted
were to disappear...
くりかえす 輪廻の流れ辿り
kurikaesu innen no nagare tadori
Following the recurring paths of fate.
終わらない世界の宿命を見つめてる
owaranai sekai no shukumei wo mitsumeteru
I gaze upon the never-ending world's destiny.
くりかえし 詠われる者達よ
kurikaeshi utawareru mono tachi yo
Oh the ones being sung continuously
守られてまどろむ宵
mamorarete madoromu you ni
be protected and sleep.
The Mediator